Ye Huang

+358 46 523 6667 sysuhuangye@gmail.com https://yehuang.me/

Profile

A big fan of web technologies and data visualisation with a strong background in Geoinformatics. Highly developed skills in Javascript, Ruby and Python with 4 years of hands-on experience in web development ranging from rich client applications to complex web services. To know more about me, please visit my personal website.

Experience

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, TIETO OY, HELSINKI, FINLAND - 06/2016 - 01/2017

- ▶ Telematics (06/2016 01/2017) Front-end Developer

 Participating design and development of a IoT & GIS-based web service whose main tech-stack is made up of React, Flux, Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, MySQL, Java, ElasticSearch, Swagger, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Sketch, Webflow and Atlassian(Jira, Confluence and Bitbucket).
- ▶ UPM 4Maint (01/2017 Present) <u>UPM</u> Consultant & SW Developer Proposing solutions for UPM 4Maint (a HTML5 hybrid mobile app) in several aspects(role-based authentication, session expiration, SQLite database pre-preparing and preloading, cordova plugins usage, async data loading and binding, etc). Developing a prototype for demonstration in using Angular2, Ionic2, TypeScript, RxJS, Cordova, SQLite, Auth0, Firebase.

WEB DEVELOPER, SOLUE OY; HELSINKI, FINLAND - 05/2014 - 05/2016

- ▶ Palkkaaminut CMS (11/2015 12/2015) <u>Palkkaaminut.fi</u> Front-end Developer Cooperating with designers to craft HTML mockups for <u>www.palkkaaminut.fi</u> based on Craft CMS, ¡Query and Bootstrap.
- Fysios CMS (11/2015) <u>Fysios Group</u> Front-end Developer Participating the development of <u>Fysios</u> which is built on Craft CMS and integrated with Knockout.js and Foundation on the client-side.
- ▶ Witrafi Admin CMS (06/2015 12/2015) <u>Witrafi Oy</u> Front-end Developer Designing and developing the client-side based on Witrafi's RESTful APIs, AngularJS and Bootstrap. Other tools for project management and testing included Yeoman, Grunt, Bower, Protractor and Jira.
- Grocialist (06/2015 11/2015) <u>Grocialist Oy</u> Front-end Developer Developing the client-side based on Grocialist's Restful APIs. The main tech-stack was made up of AngularJS, Facebook APIs, jQuery and Bootstrap.
- AngularFire-Ionic Live Chat Room (02/2015 03/2015) Solue Oy Web Developer This project was a HTML5 hybrid mobile app for live chat and was originally designed to test the real-time feature of Firebase and the performance of Ionic on mobile platforms.
- ▶ Witrafi Cloud Parking Service (10/2014 08/2015) Witrafi Oy Front-end Developer Crafting a seamless client-server integration with Angular JS, Bootstrap, Witrafi's RESTful APIs,

GoogleMap APIs and Solinor Payment APIs. Other tools contained Yeoman, Grunt, Jira and Slack.

- FinMeas HTML5 Hybrid Mobile App (09/2014 04/2015) FinMeas Oy Coordinator/Tester Proposing potential technical architectures, creating mobile app mockups in using AngularJS and Sencha Touch, coordinating project by Jira/Bitbucket/Slack and testing products before the final release.
- Aemdee Medical Online Service (05/2014 09/2014) Solue Oy Full-stack Developer Participating design and development of Aemdee web service as a full-stack developer in using Ruby on Rails, Backbone.js, jQuery, D3.js, CoffeeScript, Bootstrap and MySQL.
- Diktamen/QuattroFolia/GloPos (05/2014 10/2015) <u>Diktamen Oy/Quattro Folia Oy/GloPos Technologies</u> QA Tester

Designing, documenting and implementing manual and functional test cases for Diktamen (A Healthcare App on Android, iOS and WP), QuattroFolia (A Healthcare App on Android) and GloPos (An Indoor Positioning App on Android), while reporting, tracking and managing bugs/features/improvements on Jira.

WEB DEVELOPER FREELANCER; HELSINKI, FINLAND - 08/2015 - 12/2015

▶ Tapio Wirkkala and Rut Bryk Archive (08/2015 - 12/2015) - <u>TWRB Foundation</u> - Web Developer Crafting the technical solution and mockups, manipulating seed datasets by using FileMaker and building the <u>application</u> on top of AngularJS, Firebase and AWS S3/CloudFront CDN.

Education

- > Aalto University, Finland Master's Degree in Geoinformatics, 2012 Present
- Sun Yat-sen University, China Bachelor's Degree in Geoinformatics, 2008 2012

Skills

- ▶ Programming languages and Databases: Javascript (AngularJS, React, Relay, ExtJS, Knockout.js, Sails, Koa.js), CSS(Sass/Less, Bootstrap, Foundation, Semantic-UI), Ruby (RoR), GraphQL, MongoDB, PostGIS, MySQL
- Tools & Cloud Services: NPM, Grunt, Gulp, JSPM, Webpack, Jasmine, Karma, Protractor, Git, Bitbucket, Atlassian, Travis CI, Circle CI, AWS, GCP, Heroku, Firebase
- ▶ Visualisations: D3.js, Google Visualization, Tableau, ArcGIS, OpenGeo Suite(Geoserver, OpenLayers), Mapbox, CartoDB, Matlab, AI/PS

References

- Github, Linkedin, Personal Website
- ▶ Tel: +358 46 523 6667
- ▶ Email: sysuhuangye@gmail.com